# ANIL KUMAR PANDIYA

JavaScript Developer

anilpandiya05@gmail.com

+91 9672598162



SOCIAL



🌪 PROFILE

anilpandiya.github.io linkedin.com/in/anilpandiya github.com/Anilpandiya

I am a professional Software Engineer, Having 5 years of technical experience in IT. Proficient in developing Single Page Apps using React Ecosystem. As a developer worked in all phases of project life cycles. Strong learning curve in adapting quickly to emerging technologies.



### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Senior Software Engineer Pregin

Jun 2020 - present

- Building FinTech product Pregin Pro & Pregin Cura apps
- Preqin Pro is being developed using React ecosystem and used Rest APIs as backend architecture to access the Mongo database.
- Pregin Cura is developed on Micro frontend architecture.
- Developed ESG components for both apps.
- Working on a custom UI components library for internal use.
- Handle deployment and release process for the project.

#### Software Engineer iBASEt

Apr 2019 - Jun 2020

- Developed Solumina Product for Lockheed Martin, Air Bus
- Added reusable components and published them as npm packages.
- Build a native mobile app Unit info for android and ios.
- · Contributed in post-production activities such as Defect Fixing, Performance Tuning and Framework Upgradation.

# Senior Analyst Capgemini

Jul 2017 - Apr 2019

- · Application is being developed using Angular 6 framework and used Rest APIs as backend architecture to access the Oracle database.
- · Developed many CR's as well for different regions based on specific requirements and worked on maintaining versions.
- Planned new designs and functionality and developed modules.

IBM, Jaipur May 2016 - Jun 2017

- · Contributed on existing application Security Management System's enhancements
- Prepared MD50 and knowledge management documents.



Intern

## EXPERTISE

React & React native Angular Framework JavaScript, TypeScript Micro Frontend Architecture HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap Material UI, SASS Redux, Redux-Saga RxJS, Axios, Lodash



# OTHER SKILLS

GraphQL, Node JS Ionic, Expo AWS IAM, CI/CD REST APIs, Zipkin MySQL, Mongo DB Team City StackBlitz, FireBase Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket



EDUCATION

#### **Bachelor Of Technology CSE**

SKIT M&G, Jaipur 2013 - 2017. 74.03%

Senior Secondary GSSS. Bhilwara 2012 70.06%